A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Audiovisual materials, Series 39 FA756
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Audiovisual materials, Series 39
1945-1976
Rockefeller Archive Center
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller).
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
FA756
1 Reels Actual extent unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Audio and video pertaining to NAR's gubernatorial and political career.
Arrangement
Arranged in subseries by file type.
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller).; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Films, 1945-1976; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Footage from campaigns, conventions, and official events that are specifically related to political activities in the life of NAR. Many dozens of campaign commercials, including TV and radio spots.
  Arrangement
  Chronological.
  - Undated
    Conditions Governing Access
    When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from access at the discretion of RAC.
    - WNBF-TV Interview with NAR, pre 1958 (Reel AV 1258)
      Scope and Contents note
      Interview with Nelson Rockefeller about George Hindman and the State Constitutional Commission (filmed pre-1958).
      File Plan
      III 14.1 Fa 107
    - Homenaje a los Alcaldes de Puerto Rico (Reel AV 1116)
      produced by the Miller Brewing Company, footage of awards dinner with Governor Nelson Rockefeller and other speakers, featuring Miller High Life beers as sponsor. Also has footage of the Puerto Rico Day Parade in Manhattan.
  - 1945
    - United Nations Conference with U.S. Delegates 1945 (Reel AV 1656, Box 1, Dvd AV 1656)
      Nelson Rockefeller is shown at beginning of international conference
      III 14.1 Fb 55
    - Pan-American Day, 1945 April 14 (Reel AV 1618)
      Presentation of a proclamation from Connecticut Governor Raymond B. Baldwin to Secretary of State Nelson Rockefeller.
      III 14.5-13
  - 1958
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Shots from Fox News, 1958 (Reel AV 1700, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.38)
      A newsreel compilation from 1958 of Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial footage. Includes footage of Nelson A. Rockefeller in New York City at a reception for his gubernatorial campaign, Dwight D. Eisenhower arriving in New York City, Nelson A. Rockefeller and Dwight D. Eisenhower in 5th Avenue parade, John D. Rockefeller 3rd with Senator Keating, construction of the Interfaith Center, Nelson A. Rockefeller family portrait, President Eisenhower with Nelson Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller and David Kennedy, Nelson A. Rockefeller campaiging in Glen Falls, New York. Nelson A. Rockefeller and wife visiting Venezuela. Nelson A. Rockefeller in Albany, New York at swearing in ceremony and celeration. Mrs. Nelson A. Rockefeller and Nelson sewing union labels on clothing.
      III 14.5-10
    - Dewey Endorsement of Republican Candidates, 1958 (Reel AV 1544)
      1958 campaign, Thomas Dewey's endorsements of candidates Nelson Rockefeller, Wilson, Keating, and Lefkowitz, shot by CBS.
      III 14.1 Fd 5
    - Kenneth Keating, 1958 (Reel AV 1558)
      1958 Campaign: footage of President Eisenhower and Senator Javits visiting with candidate Keating.
      III 14.1 Fd 4
    - Rockefeller on the Issues: Speaking From the Desk, 1958 (Reel AV 1543)
      episode 12 of a series of broadcast speeches during the 1958 campaign, produced by the NYS Republican Committee.
      III 14.1 Fd 1
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1958 January 12 (Reel AV 1073)
      III 14.1 Fe 69
    - NAR on the Issues of Organized Labor, 1958 October 20 (Reel AV 1530)
      Remarks of Governor Rockefeller from the New York Republican state Committee Meeting
      III 14.1 Fd 2
    - Senator Javits Speech, 1958 October 20 (Reel AV 1559)
      Senator Javits speech on behalf of NAR gubernatorial campaign
      III 14.1 Fd 3
    - Five Candidates: Rockefeller on the Issues, 1958 (Reel AV 1659)
      1958 show with Rockefeller, Keating, Wilson, Lefkowitz and Lundy.
      III 14.1 Fb 50
    - Keating Interview, 1958 (Reel AV 1655)
      III 14.1 Fb 51
  - 1959
    - NAR on Meet the Press, 1959 July 19. (Reel AV 1082)
      Interviews with Governor Rockefeller.
      III 14.1 Ff 11
    - Paul Coates Show Interview with Governor Rockefeller, 1959 December 1 (Reel AV 1083)
      III 14.1 Ff 12
  - 1960
    - Governor Rockefeller Reports: Budget, 1960 (Reel AV 1678)
      A discussion with Senator Austin Erwin, finance commissioner, from a series of broadcast reports filmed by CBS.
      III 14.1 Fd 49
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1960 July 3 (Reel AV 1079)
      III Ff 13
    - Making of the President (Reel AV 1148)
      Based on the book by Theodore H. White, this documentary film follows the campaigns of Nixon and JFK during the 1960 presidential election, with news footage of Nelson Rockefeller, Hubert Humphreys, and others. Produced by David Wolper for ABC News.
      III 14.1 Fg 36
    - 1960 National Campaign "LEADERSHIP", "ECONOMIC GROWTH", "EQUAL OPPORTUNITY", "FOREIGN POLICY" (Reel AV 1184)
      Titles include E-20-15 LEADERSHIP; E-20-16 ECONOMIC GROWTH; E-20-17 EQUAL OPPORTUNITY; E-20-18 FOREIGN POLICY.
      III 14.1 Fa 30
      Related Materials
      ALSO SEE III 14.1 Fa 81 (AV 1232); COMPILED ON ONE REEL WITH AV #1232-1234.
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Endorses Nixon in His Campaign for Presidency, 1960; 2 reels. AV 1542A is a picture negative and AV 1542B is the soundtrack to AV 1542A. (Reel AV 1542A, Reel AV 1542B)
      Governor Rockefeller and President Eisenhower endorse Nixon as the Republican presidential candidate.
      III 14.1 Fd 15
    - National Campaign: Eisenhower for Nixon, 1960 (Reel AV 1234)
      Footage from Channel E-24 of the New York Republican State Committee, during the 1960 presidential election.
      III 14.1 Fa 83
    - National Campaign: GOP National Convention 1960 (Reel AV 1146)
      Footage of Barry M. Goldwater's speech at the 1960 GOP Convention, 'withdrawing his candidacy in support of Richard Nixon. Goldwater speaks about the history and purpose of the Republican party, and asks for unity within the party,
      III 14.1 Fd 21
    - National Campaign: Nelson A. Rockefeller on the Kennedy Record, 1960 (Reel AV 1233)
      Footage from Channel E-24 from the 1960 presidential election
      III 14.1 Fa 82
    - 1960 NATIONAL CAMPAIGN "CIVIL RIGHTS", "ECONOMIC GROWTH", "DISARMAMENT", "LEADERSHIP", Sound, Black and white, 4 minutes. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 1232)
      III 14.1 Fa 81
      E-60-11; E-60-12, E-60-13; E-60-14
  - 1961
    - Governor Rockefeller Reports: Proposals to the Legislature, 1961 January 1 (Reel AV 1683)
      One episode from a series of broadcast reports, filmed by CBS on 1961 January 1.
      III 14.1 Fd 50
    - Dr. Martin Luther King: The American Dream, 1961 July 13 (Reel AV 1102)
      Footage of Nelson Rockefeller speech about Martin Luther King Jr. at Syracuse University.
      III 14.1 Fe 47
    - Dr. Martin Luther King: The American Dream, 1961-07-13; Sound, no picture, 60 minutes. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 1103)
      III 14.1 Fe 48
      Soundtrack of Nelson A. Rockefeller speech with Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. delivered at Syracuse University.
  - 1962
    - Pre-Convention Campaign Commercials., 1962
      Contains about 40 commercials from NAR's 1962 Gubernatorial campaign. Some duplicates or revised versions included.
      - Aid to Labor, 1962 (Reel AV 1176)
      - Aid to New York City, 1962 (Reel AV 1225, Reel AV 1224)
      - Atomic Research, 1962 (Reel AV 1177)
      - Civil Rights and the Aged, 1962 (Reel AV 1183)
        III 14.1 Fa 29
      - College, 1962 (Reel AV 1162)
        III 14.1 Fa 8
      - College Education, 1962 (Reel AV 1167, Reel AV 1158, Reel AV 1169)
      - Conservation and Recreation, 1962 (Reel AV 1178)
      - Education, 1962 (Reel AV 1174)
      - Fiscal Integrity, 1962 (Reel AV 1175)
      - Higher Education, 1962 (Reel AV 1180)
      - Highway Construction, 1962 (Reel AV 1179)
      - Housing, 1962 (Reel AV 1168)
        III 14.1 Fa 14
      - Housing and Urban Renewal, 1962 (Reel AV 1181)
      - Human Rights, 1962 (Reel AV 1160)
      - Jobs, 1962 (Reel AV 1165, Reel AV 1154)
      - Jobs and Economic Growth, 1962 (Reel AV 1230)
      - Law and Narcotics, 1962 (Reel AV 1182)
      - Money, 1962 (Reel AV 1166)
      - NAR: Albany, 1962 (Reel AV 1171)
      - NAR: Buffalo, 1962 (Reel AV 1172)
      - NAR: New York City, 1962 (Reel AV 1173)
      - Narcotics, 1962 (Reel AV 1231)
      - New Yorker, 1962 (Reel AV 1164)
      - Record, 1962 (Reel AV 1226)
      - Record, New York City, 1962 (Reel AV 1159, Reel AV 1222, Reel AV 1227)
      - Record, Upstate, 1962 (Reel AV 1228, Reel AV 1223)
      - School Aid, 1962 (Reel AV 1170, Reel AV 1161, Reel AV 1157)
      - Senior Citizens, 1962 (Reel AV 1156)
      - Women, 1962 (Reel AV 1163)
      - Housing, 1962 (Reel AV 1229)
        Sound, Black and white, 5 minutes. Only available on 16mm.
        III 14.1 Fa 78
    - 1962 Address to the New York State Legislature, 1962 January 1 (Reel AV 1716, Reel AV 1717)
      CBS coverage of state address by Governor Rockefeller.
      III 14.1 Fg 5 (AV 1717) and III 14.1 Fg 4 (AV 1716).
    - NAR on At The Source, 1962 January (Reel AV 1084)
      III 14.1 Ff 14
    - NAR on Newsmakers, 1962 October 21 (Reel AV 1094)
      III 14.1 Ff 15
    - Pure Water Bonds Proposition 1 Commercials, 1963 (Reel AV 1204, Reel AV 1205, Reel AV 1207, Reel AV 1206)
      Several public service announcements that ran on TV in 1963 in support of Pure Bond issues.
    - Gov Rockefeller Swearing-In Official Highlights, 1962 December 31 (Reel AV 1545)
      Shot at Albany Executive Mansion.
      III 14.1 Fa 60
  - 1963
    - Governor Rockefeller Inauguration, 1963 January 1 (Reel AV 1666)
      III 14.1 Fd 26
    - NAR on Newsmakers, 1963 February 23 (Reel AV 1095)
      III 14.1 Ff 16
    - Interview on Latin American Common Market Affairs, 1963 March 13 (Reel AV 1086)
      Governor Rockefeller interviewed for KRNT-TV in Des Moines, Iowa
      III 14.1 Fe 16
    - Episode of Meet the Press, 1963 September 15 (Reel AV 1267)
      Episode begins with NBC coverage of the bombing of an African-American church in Birmingham, Alabama. Followed by episode of Meet the Press hosted by Ned Brooks. Includes original commercials. Filmed during presidential campaign.
      III 14.1 Ff 17
    - Visit to Colby Junior College, 1963 October 19 (Reel AV 1257)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Governor Rockefeller with wife, Happy, visiting Colby Junior College
      III 14.1 Fa 106
    - Pure Waters Conference, 1963 November 12 (Reel AV 1221)
      WRGB footage from the Pure Waters Conference held in the Capitol Building, Albany, after passage of the Pure Waters Bond Issue Prop #1.
      III 14.1 Fa 70
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1963 November 17 (Reel AV 1097)
      episode filmed during presidential campaign
      III 14.1 Ff 22
    - Nelson Rockefeller: The Man and His Record, 1963 (Reel AV 1561A, Reel AV 1561B)
      Campaign film produced during the 1963 gubernatorial race. Includes brief 'life history of NAR and footage of him at Princeton, Rockefeller Center, and in Latin America. Showcases NAR's experiences, shows him with political associates, amid NY industries and farms, visiting SUNY schools and as commissioner of the Human Rights Office.
      III 14.1 Fd 11
  - 1964
    - NAR and Staff (Reel AV 1066)
      Brief clip of Nelson Rockefeller with his staff at West 55th Street office; shot by Wolper Productions for campaign film "Making of the President 1964".
    - 1964 California: San Diego, Kiwanis Club (Reel AV 1587)
      III 14.1 Fe 5
    - Rockefeller's Way, 1964 (Reel AV 1251)
      Campaign spot from 1964 California primary
      III 14.1 Fa 100
    - The Extremists, 1964 (Reel AV 1155)
      A never-aired 1964 campaign film produced by Nelson Rockefeller And Dave Garroway about the Minutemen, the John Birch Society, and other extremist groups.
      III 14.1 Fe 70
    - Gov. Rockefeller Interrupted by Baby, 1964 February 28 (Reel AV 75)
      Nelson Rockefeller speech about opposing unilateral negations with Russia interrupted a baby laughing, during New Hampshire primary.
      III 14 F 26
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1964 March 8 (Reel AV 1081)
      Filmed during presidential campaign.
      III 14.1 Fg 38
    - Gov. Rockefeller in New Orleans, 1964 April (Reel AV 1087)
      Speech on Inter-American affairs.
      III 14.1 Fd 20
    - 1964 Campaign Interview, 1964 June 1 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1387, Reel AV 1941)
      Nelson Rockefeller interview on The Irv Kupcinet Show during presidential campaign.
      III 14.1 Fg 16
    - NAR Address to the Republican National Convention (Reel AV 1099, Box 2, Dvd AV 1099)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Two copies of access DVD.
      III 14.1 Fe 2
    - Gov. Rockefeller Speech at Stanford University, 1964 (Reel AV 1697)
      Speech about the UN during California primary
      III 14.1 Fd 23
    - Gov. Rockefeller Speech at UCLA, 1964 (Reel AV 1077)
      Nelson Rockefeller speech outdoors at UCLA, then inside for question/answer session with students during California primary.
      III 14.1 Fd 24
    - Gov. Rockefeller in Palm Springs and San Diego, 1964 (Reel AV 1268)
      Campaigning during California primary.
      III 14.1 Fg 3
    - 1964 Address to the New York State Legislature (Reel AV 1076)
      Governor Rockefeller annual address to the state legislature, filmed in Albany, NY.
      III 14.1 Fd 28
    - 1964 Oregon Primary (Reel AV 1235)
      footage of Nelson Rockefeller campaigning throughout Oregon during presidential campaign, with some nonpolitical footage of wildlife, landscapes, and aerial views of the state.
      III 14.1 Fa 84
  - 1965
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1965 July 25 (Reel AV 1089)
      III 14.1 Ff 18
    - Orange, Chenango and St. Lawrence County Fairs, 1965 August (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.9, Reel AV 1597)
      Nelson Rockefeller with wife at NY county fairs.
      III 14.1 Fe 17
    - Camp Drum, Monroe, and Steuben County Fairs, 1965 August (Reel AV 1596, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.9)
      Nelson Rockefeller with wife at public events around the state.
      III 14.1 Fe 18
    - Gov Rockefeller and Wife at Fort Schuyler, Bronx, NY, 1965 August 24 (Reel AV 1556, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Footage of military ship "Empire State IV" arriving at Fort Schuyler in the Bronx; crowds of families waiting to greet sailors. Shot by Hal Posner.
      III 14.1 Fb 12
    - Adirondack: Horseback Ride Through Forest Preserve, 1965 October 10 (Reel AV 1214, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.38)
      edited footage from UPI Commercial News Service provided to New York State television stations.
      III 14.1 Fa 62
    - Gov. Rockefeller at Dr. King's Ebenezer Church in Atlanta GA, 1965 October 17 (Reel AV 1696, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Governor Rockefeller visits Ebenezer Church in Atlanta with Reverend Martin Luther King Sr. and Jr.
      III 14.1 Fd 33
    - UN Plaza Dedication, 1965 October 25 (Reel AV 1546, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10)
      Ceremony and presentation of memorial stairway and flagpole in honor of Dog Hammarskjold, secretary-president of the United Nations, at UN Plaza in New York City.
      III 14.1 Fa 64
    - Man in Office, 1965 October 31 (Reel AV 1752)
      Governor Rockefeller interviewed by Joe Michaels on NBC.
      III 14.1 Ff 24
    - NAR on Issues and Answers, 1965 November 7 (Reel AV 1639)
      III 14.1 Ff 20
    - Gov. Rockefeller Receives Award from Nation Council of Christians and Jews, 1965 November 15 (Reel AV 1216)
      CBS footage of award ceremony at Hilton Hotel in NYC
      III 14.1 Fa 65
  - 1966
    - 1966 Campaign Commercials (Reel AV 1147)
      Sample reel of campaign commercials from 1966 gubernatorial race.
      III 14.1 Fd 54
    - The Time is Now, 1966 (Reel AV 1109)
      Political film produced by the Republican National Finance Committee before the 1966 election. Discusses domestic and international issues that have been caused by the Democratic majority in the U.S., with sound bites from Eisenhower, Ford, Nixon, Gov. Rockefeller, and others.
    - Friend of the Rockefeller Team: Campaign Commercials 1, 1966 (Reel AV 1110)
      Compilation of 31 political ads from 1966 campaign, ranging from 10 to 60 seconds each. Topics include: Pure Water Program, state scholarships, the Bureau of Consumer Protection, Medicaid, the narcotics reform laws, education, minimum wage, air pollution, and a message from Jacob Javits.
    - Friend of the Rockefeller Team: Campaign Commercials 2, 1966 (Reel AV 1114)
      Compilation of 4 campaign commercials produced for the 1966 campaign (?): "4 R's" (education),"Pay Envelope" (jobs), "Consumer Fraud" (consumer protection), "Detective" (criminal intelligence system).
    - 1966 Address to the New York State Legislature, 1966 January 5 (Reel AV 1739)
      footage of Governor Rockefeller address, shot by the NYS Department of Commerce
      III 14.1 Fg 6
    - The State Vs. the Addict, 1966 March 6 (Reel AV 1075)
      Panel discussion with Nelson Rockefeller, Donald Louria, Wyatt Tee Walker, interviewed by Bill Beutel and Murphy Martin.
      III 14.1 ff 37
    - Opening of Republican State Committee Campaign Headquarters, 1966 June 6 (Reel AV 1220, Box 2, Dvd AV 1220)
      from 1966 campaign, footage of Governor Rockefeller, Governor Malcolm Wilson, Attn. General Louis Lefkowitz at the Hilton Hotel in NYC.
      III 14.1 Fa 69
    - Formal Announcement of Candidacy, 1966 April 6 (Reel AV 1583, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.10, Reel AV 1591)
      Nelson Rockefeller announces his intention to run for governor
      III 14.1 Fe 14 (AV 1591) and III 14.1 Fe 15 (AV 1583)
    - Labor and the Public Employee, 1966 May 15 (Reel AV 1753)
      Discussion between Nelson Rockefeller, George Taylor, and Mort Dean, shown live on CBS.
      III 14.1 Ff 38
    - Governor Rockefeller's Acceptance Speech, 1966 September (Reel AV 1599)
      NAR acceptance speech at the GOP State Convention, with an introduction from Senator Jacob Javits, broadcast live.
      III 14.1 Fe 19
    - Election Night Victory, 1966 November 8 (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.11, Reel AV 3.11)
      Highlights of NAR victory speech at Hilton Hotel in New York, Footage of Lieutenant Governor Malcolm Wilson, Attorney General Louis Lefkowitz, and State Comptroller Charles Wilson.
      III 14.1 Fe 61
  - 1967
    - Governor NAR 1967 Inauguration, 1967 January 2 (Reel AV 1740, Box 2, Dvd AV 1379)
      Inauguration in the Assembly Chamber in Albany, NY. Benediction is given by Dr. Sandy Ray of the Cornerstone Baptist Church in Brooklyn, NY.
      III 14.1 Fg 10
    - Annual Message to Legislature, 1967 January 4 (Reel AV 1862)
      Unedited footage of NAR annual address in the Assembly Chambers in Albany, NY.
      III 14.1 Fg 12-Fg 15
  - 1968
    - Rockefeller - The Presidential Man, 1968 (Reel AV 1765)
      30-minute version of campaign film, with introduction by Lieutenant General James Gavin. Produced by Robert Drew Films.
      III 14.1 Fe 26
    - Rockefeller - The Man Who Can, 1968; AV 1815: 16mm motion picture film AV 10631: 2" Quad video reel (Reel AV 1815, Reel AV 10631)
      Access copy unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
      One-hour version of campaign film. Produced by Robert Drew Films
    - Annual Message to Legislature, 1968 January 3 (Reel AV 1820, Reel AV 1814)
      Unedited footage of NAR annual speech to the New York State Legislature, filmed in the Assembly Room at the Capitol in Albany, NY.
    - Episode of Panorama with NAR, 1968 February (Reel AV 1743)
      A BBC program from 1968 February which includes some footage used in the 1964 biographical film, "The Nelson Rockefeller Story"
      III 14.1 Ff 21
    - Declaration of Non-Candidacy, 1968 March 21 (Reel AV 1085)
      In speech at the Hilton Hotel in NYC, Nelson Rockefeller declares he will not run for the 1968 presidency, in New York.
      III 14.1 Fg 7 - Fg 9
    - Declaration as Active Candidate, 1968 April 30 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1385, Reel AV 1569)
      Nelson Rockefeller reverses his previous announcement about the 1968 presidency, in Philadelphia, PA.
      III 14.1 Fb 13
    - Rockefeller Statement, 1968 April 30 (Reel AV 1661)
      NAR declares his candidacy, in Albany NY.
      III 14.1 Fe 23
    - Gov. Rockefeller at World Affairs Council in Philadelphia, 1968 May 1 (Reel AV 1089)
      NAR address on foreign policy, "The Building of a Just World Order"
      III 14.1 Fg 18
    - 1968 Republican National Convention, 1968 August 7-8 (Reel AV 1634, Box 1, Dvd 3.15, Reel AV 1635)
      Footage NAR, Winthrop Rockefeller, and others from convention; nomination of NAR by Gov. Raymond Schafer (PA); thank-you speeches from NAR and wife; other footage from NBC.
      III 14.1 Fe 24 (AV 1634) and III 14.1 Fe 25 (AV 1635)
    - Crime Control Week, 1968 December (Reel AV 1112)
      TV spot on the State Police sent to all local TV stations for use during the week of 1968 December 2.
      III 14.1 Fa 68
    - 1968 Year-End Interview, 1968 December 20 (Reel AV 1362, Box 2, Dvd AV 1362)
      NAR interview by Gabe Pressman
      III 14.1 Ff 48
    - Speech at Polish Home Picnic in Auburn NY, 1968 (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.3, Reel AV 1246)
      NAR speech during presidential campaign filmed by Mrs. Dorcas Tucker of North Carolina.
      III 14.1 Fa 95
  - 1969
    - Message to Legislature, 1969 January 8 (Reel AV 1943, Reel AV 1942)
      NAR annual message to the NYS legislature, Albany, NY.
      III 14.1 Fg 19 (AV 1942) and III 14.1 Fg 20 (AV 1943)
    - 1969 Town Meeting with Gov. Rockefeller, 1969 January 29 (Reel AV 1748)
      Town meetings at Roberson Center in Binghamton, NY and Howard Johnson in Elmira, NY.
      III 14.1 Ff 36
    - A New Crown for the Empire State, 1969 May (Box 2, Dvd AV 1388, Reel AV 1857, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.43)
      NBC News piece about the reconstruction of the South Mall in Albany, NY. Broadcast on New York Illustrated, 1969 May.
      III 14.1 Fg 23
    - Today Show Interview with NAR, 1969 May 13 (Box 1, Dvd 3.16, Reel AV 1679)
      Aline Saarinen of NBC News interviews NAR about gift of primitive art collection to the Metropolitan Museum of Art, intercut with scenes of exhibition and featured pieces.
      III 14.1 Fb 56
    - Rockefeller Visit to Binghamton, Broome County, NY, 1969 November 19 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1363, Reel AV 1363)
      NAR visits proposed site of new state building, speaks at rally
      III 14.1 Fg 29
    - 1969 Year-End Review, 1969 December 10 (Reel AV 1101)
      NAR interviewed by Glover Delany, president of NYS Broadcasters Association, and filmed by Hal Posner.
      III 14.1 Ff 44
  - 1970
    - 1970 Rockefeller Campaign Commercials (Reel AV 1837)